<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>androwis</title>
 <link href="http://androw.is/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://androw.is/"/>
 <updated>2012-12-22T13:11:09-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://androw.is</id>
 <author>
   <name>androwis abumoussa</name>
   <email>androwis@androw.is</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Ruby Conf</title>
   <link href="http://androw.is/ruby-conf"/>
   <updated>2012-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http:/androw.is/ruby-conf</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ruby conf was the first conference I went to where I felt adequately unprepared for. having only been introduced to the world of ruby only a few weeks prior,I was a complete newcomer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What blew me away was the community. it was intimate conference, but one that was super international. first time I experienced that. there the bad assets were genuinely interested in meeting everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;design was taken seriously&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;morals were most importantly upheld&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;teaching was the goal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;differences between some of the other conferences like ricon2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;case s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='embed tweet'&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best feature of the Ruby language is its people. Thanks, humans of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search/%23rubyconf&quot;&gt;#rubyconf&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; you made this thing great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sarah Mei (@sarahmei) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sarahmei/status/265241470984925184&quot; data-datetime=&quot;2012-11-04T23:57:49+00:00&quot;&gt;November 4, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Pushing Boundary</title>
   <link href="http://androw.is/pushing-the-boundary"/>
   <updated>2012-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http:/androw.is/pushing-the-boundary</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Distributed systems really excite me. My time at &lt;a href=&quot;http://simply-home.com&quot;&gt;Simply Home&lt;/a&gt; taught me how to use information from networked devices to change people&amp;rsquo;s lives. Viewing social media as a distributed system of human sensors lead to an exploration of twitter as an indicator for disease spread at &lt;a href=&quot;http://fount.in&quot;&gt;Fountin&lt;/a&gt;. Both of these projects are the driving motivation for my Ph.D. work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;d like to convince you of through this post is that data aggregration, though important, is really only the first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed systems, at least to me, can be viewed as platforms to inform all sorts of decisions. Analytics are really awesome at generating data, but these tools have a hard time automating insights. I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a system that is able to relieve users from having to constantly search and monitor for trends or edge cases. I believe tools should remove the fatigue associated with that responsibility and replace it with the opportunity to explore the data and augment (read: train) the feedback that the system provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.underconsideration.com/brandnew/archives/boundary_logo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Boundary&quot; /&gt;
Along these lines, I&amp;rsquo;d like to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://boundary.com&quot;&gt;Boundary&lt;/a&gt; as an example since it helps me scale. Essentially, their product allows developers to map the topology of distributed applications fast, so we can focus on harder things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Here is &lt;font style=&quot;color:#D7003E; font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;Boundary&lt;/font&gt; from a 50k foot view&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They do a great job of introducing their product. If you want to monitor the performance of a distributed system, take the time to learn about them &lt;a href=&quot;http://boundary.com/why-boundary/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://boundary.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/home-how-it-works-product.png&quot; title=&quot;Boundary's beautiful logo&quot; alt=&quot;Boundray's Workflow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell you want to use Boundary because distributed systems communicate a lot and that communication is often the bottle neck wrt performance. Boundary enables me to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuously measure how [much] systems communicate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify bottlenecks or edge cases [kind-of] .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handle bottlenecks or edge cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Again, Boundary does most of the heavy lifting, leaving you with an organizational task of sifting through the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Here is how to deploy &lt;font style=&quot;color:#D7003E; font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;Boundary&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their product is dead simple. Deploy their tools on the machines you want to analyze (I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://puppetlabs.com/blog/introducing-puppet-labs-boundary-module/&quot;&gt;puppet&lt;/a&gt; for personal projects, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/boundary/boundary_cookbooks/tree/master/apps&quot;&gt;chef&lt;/a&gt; for work.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Setup &lt;font style=&quot;color:#D7003E; font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;Boundary&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, Boundary is bulit to allow you to take your system and:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;What I would love to see happen with the platform is that the data available to Boundary becomes a training bed for all sorts of machine learning to augment system monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;font style=&quot;color:#D7003E; font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;Boundary&lt;/font&gt; with crumbtrails.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;http://basho.com/community/ricon2012/&quot;&gt;Ricon 2012&lt;/a&gt; Dietrich talked about putting data into context. The knowledge of a system&amp;rsquo;s architecture helps developers understand what&amp;rsquo;s happening, why, where and when. Something I&amp;rsquo;d really love to see Boundary do is to allow developers to log events in their code (something akin to &lt;a href=&quot;http://engineering.twitter.com/2012/06/distributed-systems-tracing-with-zipkin.html&quot;&gt;Twitter&amp;rsquo;s Zipken&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-b0r71ZbJdmA/T9DYhbE0uXI/AAAAAAAAABs/bXwyM76Iddc/s1600/web-screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter's Zipkin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tool like this, baked into Boundary, would allow the system to learn how the individual connections within the application layers affect network utilizations.  More importantly, with this level of organization comes context that can be shared among teams of developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;font style=&quot;color:#D7003E; font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;Boundary&lt;/font&gt; Tails.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://controls.engin.umich.edu/wiki/images/b/bd/Tails.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Tail Distributions&quot; /&gt;
From a DevOps standpoint there are a number of ways to configure server clusters. Each configuration gives rise to different interactions for edge cases. This is not fun to debug under load or scale, but they are perhaps the most important metric of a functioning system.  If you can guarantee the edge cases, then everything else is bounded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boundary allows you to programmatically define which apps are running on your node, listening to which ports. With this model you&amp;rsquo;re able to capture application specific traffic across clusters (independent of how it&amp;rsquo;s setup), which is pretty fantastic. That got me thinking, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great to get tail distributions?  I&amp;rsquo;d love to see how different parts of my application are performing (on average) in the 99%, 99.9%, 99.99%, 99.999% cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while those are being calculated, why not have the system automagically alert me of performance wins/loses as those running values change? Provide hooks where I can detect irregular or unresponsive traffic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;font style=&quot;color:#D7003E; font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;Boundary&lt;/font&gt; as an online, machine learning platform.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/time-series.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;UI for machine learning&quot; /&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;re starting to see the evolution of a well contained eco-system for a machine learning platform. I would love to see a simple selection mechanism like above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Boundary&amp;rsquo;s data, a UI  where users are able to highlight periodicities or patterns and then monitor or search for them would be incredibly valuable. Users could begin to explore their data actively in the future with these patterns and comparisons with these patterns could be used to drive other decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a mechanism like this, the representation of dynamic systems can evolve with use, be shared between developers or support teams to drive understanding of how software is interacting in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;font style=&quot;color:#D7003E; font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;Boundary&lt;/font&gt; + crowdsourced intelligence&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s tricky to explain how I envision Boundary working as a crowdsourcing agent w/out screenshots or designs, but there are really two main ideas at play here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.By giving developers tools to identify patterns of interest, Boundary is essentially generating a curated knowledge base to validate the ML techniques. With validated models, Boundary can begin driving new initiatives with user experience as they delight their users with clusters of acceptable/unacceptable runtime behavior for a given type of setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.These tools could also drive collaboration (read: engagement in business speak). Given a platform to create content (these patterns that we&amp;rsquo;re looking for) we&amp;rsquo;d be able to analyze systems together, more importantly share insights through reuse. Just as Github federated code development and made version control enjoyable, I feel like Boundary&amp;rsquo;s pretty well placed to drive the same innovation with system scaling and monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Switch to Github Pages</title>
   <link href="http://androw.is/the-switch-to-github-pages"/>
   <updated>2012-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http:/androw.is/the-switch-to-github-pages</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I remember meeting &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/50006538&quot;&gt;Gabe Carleton-Barnes&lt;/a&gt; while travelling around Europe.  Here was someone who had a laptop, 6 articles of clothing, and a wallet travelling around Europe for three months.  And there I was, lugging around 2 suitcases and a backpack like a douche.  I felt like I needed to hold on to everything. Not only was this limiting me in terms of mobility, but I was constantly worrying, about losing or forgetting my stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was packing for grad school, I realized the metaphor still haunted me; I owned too many things.  It was becoming a pain not only to manage my digital life (synching files between four computers), but I didn&amp;#8217;t have the luxury of easily transporting from place to place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months back, I decided to finally let go of everything.  I put up a digital store on &lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/shops/androwis&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;#8217;ve slowly been shedding since.  It&amp;#8217;s turned out to put some money in my pocket, but more importantly I feel free, not dragged down by all my crap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you start shedding, you become addicted.  I realized I was still shuffling files between machines, even though I had &lt;a href=&quot;http://db.tt/NOFhHqZw&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; (which I love!). So, I started selling my computers and put everything up at &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.  Discovering &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;: changed my life, &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;: made it easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing about Github Pages is, that it&amp;#8217;s free, allows me to direct content to my personal site, and encourages me to create and share content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My entire site is open source, &amp;#8212; of course. Perhaps it could help you get started!&lt;/p&gt;



</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>sample math file</title>
   <link href="http://androw.is/SampleMath"/>
   <updated>2012-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http:/androw.is/SampleMath</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;you can do awesome things with maths:&lt;/p&gt;
$f(|I_2|)=\left| \int_{0}^T \psi(t)
\left\{ u(a,t)-
\int_{\gamma(t)}^a
\frac{d\theta}{k(\theta,t)}
\int_{a}^\theta c(\xi)u_t(\xi,t)\,d\xi
\right\} dt
\right|$
&lt;p&gt;Like write out all the greek letters.&lt;br /&gt;
$\alpha, &lt;br /&gt;
\beta, \gamma, \Gamma,&lt;br /&gt;
\delta,\Delta,&lt;br /&gt;
\epsilon, \zeta, \eta, \theta, \Theta, \kappa,&lt;br /&gt;
\lambda, \Lambda, \mu, \nu,&lt;br /&gt;
\xi, \Xi,&lt;br /&gt;
\pi, \Pi,&lt;br /&gt;
\rho,&lt;br /&gt;
\sigma, &lt;br /&gt;
\tau,&lt;br /&gt;
\phi, \Phi,&lt;br /&gt;
\chi,&lt;br /&gt;
\psi, \Psi,&lt;br /&gt;
\omega, \Omega$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And make things look pretty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draw derivatives&lt;br /&gt;
\begin{equation}&lt;br /&gt;
\frac{dy}{dx} = \lim_{\Delta x \to 0} \frac{\Delta y}&lt;br /&gt;
{\Delta x}&lt;br /&gt;
\end{equation}&lt;br /&gt;
\begin{equation}&lt;br /&gt;
f(x) \to y \quad \mbox{as} \quad x \to&lt;br /&gt;
x_{0}&lt;br /&gt;
\end{equation}&lt;br /&gt;
\begin{equation}&lt;br /&gt;
f(x) \mathop {\longrightarrow}&lt;br /&gt;
\limits_{x \to x_0} y&lt;br /&gt;
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}&lt;br /&gt;
\log_{10}f \simeq n&lt;br /&gt;
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}&lt;br /&gt;
f(x)\sim 10^{n}&lt;br /&gt;
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximate equality:&lt;br /&gt;
\begin{equation}&lt;br /&gt;
f(x)\simeq g(x)&lt;br /&gt;
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}&lt;br /&gt;
f(x) \propto x^3 .&lt;br /&gt;
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Power of Push</title>
   <link href="http://androw.is/the-power-of-push"/>
   <updated>2012-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http:/androw.is/the-power-of-push</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love this quote from [This American Life&amp;#8217;s] Ira Glass about [pushing] something from mediocrity into the realm of something incredible: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;#8220;For me, pushing myself is way more about &amp;quot;It&amp;#8217;s hard to make something that&amp;#8217;s interesting.&amp;quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
 It&amp;#8217;s really, really hard, and I&amp;#8217;m sure we don&amp;#8217;t succeed with every story on every show. Basically, anything that anyone makes. It&amp;#8217;s like a law of nature, a law of aerodynamics, that anything that&amp;#8217;s written or anything that&amp;#8217;s created wants to be mediocre. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
 The natural state of all writing is mediocrity. It&amp;#8217;s all tending toward mediocrity in the same way that all atoms are sort of dissipating out toward the expanse of the universe. Everything wants to be mediocre, so what it takes to make anything more than mediocre is such a &lt;i&gt;fucking&lt;/i&gt; act of will. Anyone who makes something for a living, or even not for a living, if they&amp;#8217;re really excited about it.  You just have to exert so much will into something for it to be good. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
  That feels exactly the same now as it did the first week of the show. That hasn&amp;#8217;t changed at all. That&amp;#8217;s the premise of what it takes to make something.&amp;#8221;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Androwis Abumoussa's Resume</title>
   <link href="http://androw.is/resume"/>
   <updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http:/androw.is/resume</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;resume&quot; style=&quot;font-size:12px; min-width:630px&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;downloads&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/static/resume/AndrowisAbumoussaResume.txt&quot;&gt;Current Resume&lt;/a&gt;
| &lt;a href=&quot;/static/resume/AndrewAbuMoussaTranscript.pdf&quot;&gt;Unofficial &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UNC&lt;/span&gt; Transcript&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;center&gt; contact&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Androwis Abumoussa&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;tl&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; current address :&lt;/strong&gt; 57 Glasgow Street, Rochester NY 14608&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;tr&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; permanent address :&lt;/strong&gt; 100 Tarnhill Dr, Flat Rock, NC 28731&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;t&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;twitter&lt;/strong&gt;.com/&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/androwis&quot;&gt;androwis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;t&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;github&lt;/strong&gt;.com/&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/androwis&quot;&gt;androwis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;t&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:androwis@androw.is&quot;&gt;androwis@androw.is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;t&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:8283935939&quot;&gt;828.393.5939&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;education&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The University of Rochester&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt;1 / 2012 – present&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Computer Science Ph.D. Candidate&lt;br&gt;
Accessibile User Interfaces [under &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.rochester.edu/~jbigham/&quot;&gt;Dr. Jeffrey Bigham&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;br&gt;
Artificial Intelligence [under &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.rochester.edu/u/kautz/&quot;&gt;Dr. Henry Kautz&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt;8 / 2005 – 5 / 2009&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics [under &lt;a href=&quot;http://mitran.web.unc.edu/&quot;&gt;Dr. Sorin Mitran&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
B.Sc. w/ Honors in Computer Science [under &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.unc.edu/~gb/&quot;&gt;Dr. Gary Bishop&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
Mathematics &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPA&lt;/span&gt; – 3.69/4.00 Overall–3.42/4.00&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The North Carolina School of Science and Mathematics&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt;8 / 2003 – 5 / 2005&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;Fell in love with Fractals and Chaos, exhausted biology and maths curriculums, &amp;amp; surprisingly, did 0 programming.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;employment history&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-founder / &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CTO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://fount.in&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fount.in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;i&gt;Rochester, NY&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt;[May 2012 – Present]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;Artificial Intelligence as a Service.&lt;br&gt;Coverage: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popsci.com/science/article/2012-07/algorithm-scans-your-tweets-tell-you-if-youre-about-get-sick&quot;&gt;PopSci&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/5929196/how-twitter-can-predict-when-individuals-will-get-sick&quot;&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newscientist.com/blogs/onepercent/2012/07/ai-predicts-when-youre-about-t.html&quot;&gt;New Scientist&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/researchers-use-twitter-to-predict-when-new-yorkers-will-catch-the-flu-with-90-accuracy-2012-8&quot;&gt;Business Insider&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.discovery.com/tech/twitter-predicts-sickness-120726.html&quot;&gt;Discovery News&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medicaldaily.com/news/20120726/11111/twitter-algorithm-know-flu-influenza-artificial-intelligence.htm&quot;&gt; MedicalDaily&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bild.de/digital/internet/twitter/twitter-sagt-krankheit-voraus-25416408.bild.html&quot;&gt;Bild.de&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfgate.com/technology/businessinsider/article/Researchers-Use-Twitter-To-Predict-When-New-3754629.php&quot;&gt;SFGate&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fiercehealthit.com/story/twitter-helps-predict-flu-trends-new-york/2012-08-01?utm_source=rss&quot;&gt;Fierce Health&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/templates/rundowns/rundown.php?prgId=35&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (panel round 2, 5 minutes in)  | &lt;a href=&quot;http://colab.is/2012/gigtank-goes-to-washington/&quot;&gt;[video] Health Data Palooza Keynote&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/48183729&quot;&gt;GigTank Demo Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Head of Engineering&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://simply-home.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simply Home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;i&gt;Asheville, NC&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt;[Oct. 2010 – Apr. 2012]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;As the chief technologist at SimplyHome, I was responsible for building the infrastructure behind our solutions that allowed families to monitor aging or disabled loved ones with technology instead of live at home caregivers.&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Restructured and rewrote the distributed systems and cloud architecture&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Learned about hardware manufacturing through the design of ~12 devices (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; certifications, hardware tooling, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CAD&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Heavy scaling and growth focus&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Coverage:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simply-home.com/extreme/&quot;&gt;Extreme Makeover: Home Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Founder / President&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://scenedipity.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenedipity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;i&gt;Asheville, NC&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt;[Apr. 2011 – Apr. 2012]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open data platform for restaurant and foodtrucks &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Introduction to open source community (specifically &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.scenedipity.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;) and twitter.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;[Toolkit Growth]&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://d.scndp.it:5984/_utils&quot;&gt;CouchDB&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Scenedipity/embedded-jetty-archetype&quot;&gt;Embedded jetty&lt;/a&gt; w/ Virtual Hosts | Graphiti | built a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scndp.it&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; Shortener&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Scenedipity/scnd.pt&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;) &amp;amp; [&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/androwis/j&quot;&gt;one in JS!&lt;/a&gt;] | tech basis for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timesfreepress.com/news/2012/may/15/tech-challenge/?print&quot;&gt;Fount.in&lt;/a&gt; | open sourced &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/androwis/androwis.github.com&quot;&gt;http://androw.is&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Lead Dev / Sys Admin &lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://iwanna.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IWANNA&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USA&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LLC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;i&gt;Asheville, NC &lt;/i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt;[Jan. 2010 – July 2011]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Managed the complete rebuild of a classified website that serves over 25,000 classifieds weekly and generates over 1 million hits a month.  The largest developmental focus was placed on the user-interfaces and the networking of the individual advertiser&amp;#8217;s classifieds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Proposed/developed an expansion that focuses on and supports socially aware projects and programs in the local community&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Proposed/developed a marketplace for local businesses to manage and brand their inventories.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming Consultant&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bishara.com.eg/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bishara Textile Manufacturing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt; Cairo, Egypt&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt;[May 2008 –  Sept. 2008] &lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Designed an online management tool for a 2000+ worker textile factory. The software manages all aspects of garment production, from worker output and factory capacity to scheduling design calendars while using a database back-end. Resulted in a 12% productivity increase.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programmer &amp;amp; Draftsman,&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://shamburgerarchitecture.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shamburger Design Studio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;i&gt; Hendersonville, NC&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt; [May 2007 – Aug. 2007]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Web Programmer: created an ftp style page so clients could securely access rendered designs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Architectural draftsman for 10 projects in excess value of $15 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trained a new intern.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Architectural Intern, &lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://shamburgerarchitecture.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shamburger Design Studio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt; Hendersonville, NC &lt;/i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;d&quot;&gt;[May 2006 – Aug. 2006]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Apprenticed architect through all stages of design, from initial meeting with clients, to sketching the ideas, to final presentation of plans and bidding of project to contractor &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Draftsman using AutoCAD 2005, archiCAD, and Google’s Sketch-Up.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;publications&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/static/papers/Real-Time_Captioning_by_Groups_of_Non-Experts_UIST-12.pdf&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Real-Time Captioning by Groups of Non-Experts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
W Lasecki, C Miller, A Sadilek, A Abumoussa, D Borrello, R Kushalnagar, &amp;amp; J Bigham&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;in 25th &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UIST&lt;/span&gt;) 2012&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Crowd sourcing captioning to power an interface for the deaf&lt;br/&gt;
Coverage: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newscientist.com/article/mg21528745.200-crowdsourcing-serves-up-the-subtitles-to-your-life.html?&quot;&gt;New Scientist&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/5928856/crowdsourcing-could-help-deaf-people-subtitle-their-everyday-life&quot;&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/MotionVideo.js&quot; alt=&quot;distributed, realtime video processing using HTML5 &amp;amp; Javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed, Real-Time Video Processing Using HTML5 &amp;amp; Javascript&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Tutorial for using HTML5&amp;#8217;s canvas to simultaneously play and process video for computer vision processing.
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/resume/AndrewAbuMoussaHonorsThesis.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irys: : The Focus Oriented, Auditory Online User Interface&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; cs undergraduate honors thesis in accessible interfaces for the blind.    &lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/static/resume/AndrewAbuMoussaMathModeling.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analysis of the Stock Market&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
maths undergraduate honors thesis exploring possible models for stock market performance
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;center&gt;skills &lt;/center&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Languages&lt;/strong&gt; | Java, Scala, Python, C, C++, lisp, prolog, ruby&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Technologies&lt;/strong&gt; |  Spring, J2EE, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;EJB&lt;/span&gt;, Node.js, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;, Javascript/jQuery, rails&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile&lt;/strong&gt; | HTML5/JS, Android, iOS, WP7&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases&lt;/strong&gt; | CouchDB, Cassandra, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SQL&lt;/span&gt;, memchached&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symbolic Computing&lt;/strong&gt; | Mathematica, Matlab, Maple&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphic Suites&lt;/strong&gt; | Photoshop &amp;amp; Gimp, Sketch-Up&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drafting and Architectural&lt;/strong&gt; | autoCAD, archiCAD&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoken Languages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Bilingual in English and Arabic. (U.S. citizen)&lt;br&gt;Advanced French. Basic Spanish &amp;amp; German.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Honors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
University of Rochester Hajim School of Engineering Dean&amp;#8217;s Fellowship [ 2011-2012 ]&lt;br /&gt;
Semifinalist in Carolina Entrepreneurial Challenge, Kenan-Flagler Business School at &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UNC&lt;/span&gt;-CH [ 2010 ]&lt;br /&gt;
University of North Carolina Honors Program [ 2005 – 2009 ]&lt;br /&gt;
State of North Carolina Tuition Scholarship [ 2005 – 2009 ]&lt;br /&gt;
Western North Carolina Regional Scholar, The Community Foundation of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;WNC&lt;/span&gt; [ 2005 ]&lt;br /&gt;
Glaxo-Smith-Kline Scholar and Research Grant [ 2004 ]&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Certifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Skydiving, Scuba, Belay&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mentoring</title>
   <link href="http://androw.is/mentoring"/>
   <updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http:/androw.is/mentoring</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;body&quot; style=&quot;margin:auto&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/dianakimball/mentoring&quot;&gt;distributed mentoring movement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every major step forward in my life so far has been inspired and encouraged by the mentors I’ve been fortunate enough to have. I believe that hopes, dreams, and advice are best shared in ongoing, personal relationships, and it’s important to me to make myself available as a mentor to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had so many great experiences in my life, and I’d love to share them if you’re considering pursuing a similar path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2003-2006, I explored my love for art and design through the help of Wayland Shamburger of &lt;a href=&quot;http://shamburgerdesignstudio.com&quot;&gt; Shamburger Design Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2005-2009 were some of the best years of my life, as I explored the wild world of stocks with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cpc.unc.edu/people/fellows/bio?person=turchi&quot;&gt;Dr. Boone Turchi&lt;/a&gt; and numerical analysis with &lt;a href=&quot;http://mitran.web.unc.edu/&quot;&gt;Dr. Sorin Mitran&lt;/a&gt; [this man is a genius] while falling in love with computer languages thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://cs.unc.edu/~jsterrel&quot;&gt;Dr. Jeff Terrell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2008 marked my introduction into assistive technology as &lt;a href=&quot;http://cs.unc.edu/~gb&quot;&gt;Dr. Gary Bishop&lt;/a&gt; and I explored the use of an online auditory interface as a new assistive technology for the blind&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started &lt;a href=&quot;http://scenedipity.com/&quot;&gt;Scenedipity&lt;/a&gt; in 2011 as an open data platform for restaurant and food truck information. This has been my introduction to and playground for the NoSQL movement with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jshoffstall&quot;&gt;Justin Shoffstall&lt;/a&gt; who currently works for Basho&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;li&gt; I&amp;#8217;m currently Director of Engineering at &lt;a href=&quot;http://simply-home.com&quot;&gt;Simply Home&lt;/a&gt; where I develop assistive technologies and business solutions for people with disabilities.  I&amp;#8217;m also a Ph.D. candidate at the University of Rochester under the advising of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.rochester.edu/~jbigham/&quot;&gt; Dr. Jeff Bigham&lt;/a&gt; as I continue my study of dynamic user interfaces and artificial intelligence&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to work together, you can write me a letter responding to the questions below; I’ll write back to all letters I receive in this way within two weeks no matter what. In response to the most exceptional letters, I’ll propose further correspondence—and in certain cases, an ongoing mentoring relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Tell me about yourself. How did you become who you are, and who do you want to become?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. What do you hope to gain from our mentoring relationship?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. What’s the best thing you’ve read, watched, or listened to lately?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add links to any profiles or projects you’re proud of, and send it all to:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:androwis@androw.is&quot;&gt;androwis@androw.is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to learning together!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Creative Commons License&quot; src=&quot;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/80x15.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>100 Things Challenge</title>
   <link href="http://androw.is/100-things"/>
   <updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http:/androw.is/100-things</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/minimalist-fun-the-100-things-challenge/&quot;&gt;100 things challenge&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;#8217;s everything I own, sorted by value.  &lt;strong&gt;Everything here is for sale.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.autotrader.com/cars-for-sale/vehicledetails.xhtml?ownerId=66962067&amp;amp;searchRadius=0&amp;amp;listingId=314734182&quot;&gt;2007 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BMW&lt;/span&gt; 328 Coupe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/offer-listing/B007EZITDE?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;condition=used&amp;amp;seller=AVEUUKGJWKVXT&quot;&gt;11.6 Macbook Air &amp;#8211; 1.8GHz Intel Core i7, 4GB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
3. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004YLCKYA?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;seller=AVEUUKGJWKVXT&amp;amp;sn=androwis&quot;&gt;27&amp;quot; Apple Thunderbolt Display&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
4. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/offer-listing/B001XURPQI?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;condition=used&amp;amp;seller=AVEUUKGJWKVXT&quot;&gt;Canon &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;EOS&lt;/span&gt; Rebel T1i 15.1 MP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
5. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/offer-listing/B00681RUOY?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;condition=used&amp;amp;seller=AVEUUKGJWKVXT&quot;&gt;24&amp;quot; Dell Ultrasharp &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; u2412M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
6. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/offer-listing/B00681RUOY?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;condition=used&amp;amp;seller=AVEUUKGJWKVXT&quot;&gt;24&amp;quot; Dell Ultrasharp &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; u2412M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/offer-listing/B00681RUOY?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;condition=used&amp;amp;seller=AVEUUKGJWKVXT&quot;&gt;24&amp;quot; Dell inch Ultrasharp &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; u2412M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/offer-listing/B005ZEF01A?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;condition=used&amp;amp;seller=AVEUUKGJWKVXT&quot;&gt;Galaxy Nexus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/offer-listing/B003HFG6S0?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;condition=refurbished&amp;amp;seller=AVEUUKGJWKVXT&quot;&gt;Samsung PX2370 23&amp;quot; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact me with an offer, mention this post, and i&amp;#8217;ll give you a deal.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
